Deepak

React Js Developer

Faridabad (Haryana)

deepakchauhan2096@gmail.com

8447517162

linkedin.com/in/deepakchauhan2096

https://deepakports.netlify.app

Summary

Over 2+ years of extensive experience in IT industry as Front-End Web Developer with web-based applications and UI applications in various domains. experience in application and web development with emphasis on HTML/ HTML5, XML, CSS 3, JSON, DOM, JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Bootstrap.

Looking for an opportunity to work in more challenging environment at leading organization to showcase my skills in programming to generate high end solutions and making a fundamental contribution to company's success. I can also integrate the development of an ongoing web project, solo or being part of a team.

Skills / IT Skills

React Js • JSON • Material-UI • JavaScript • Redux • Tailwind CSS • Next Js • API Integration HTML5 • Bootstrap • CSS3

Experience

React Js Developer

Vervebot

May 2022 - Jan 2024 (1 year 9 months)

- Develop front-end features, components, and libraries, translating designs and wireframes into highquality, reusable code optimized for maximum performance across various web-capable devices and browsers.
- Demonstrate ability to lead and contribute to technical discussions, participating in and facilitating daily stand-ups, bi-weekly sprint planning, and sprint retrospectives.
- Conduct code reviews to ensure alignment with architectural principles and coding standards across the project lifecycle.

React Js Developer

Material Library

Jul 2021 - May 2022 (11 months)

- Develop Responsive Web Apps and Static and Dynamic Web Pages.
- Developed easy-to-use, interactive web apps.
- Api integration and DOM manipulation.

Education



J.C. Bose University of Science and Technology, YMCA

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering Aug 2017 - Dec 2021

Projects

- TryScrum.com
- TryBusinessAgility.com
- · Point of Sales (POS) Application
- Attendance Management System
- · Analytics Dashboards
- · Customer Screens

Licenses & Certifications

Responsive Web Design - freeCodeCamp https://freecodecamp.org/certification/deepak20051995/responsve-web-design

IS Web Development – Internshala

Data Structures in JAVA - Coding Ninjas Issued Jan 2023 - May 2023